<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://betaflight.com/blog</id>
    <title>Betaflight News</title>
    <updated>2024-01-01T18:23:10.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://betaflight.com/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Betaflight Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://betaflight.com/img/betaflight/icon_light.svg</icon>
    <rights>Copyright © 2024 All rights reserved BetaFlight Team</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[HQProp - Betaflight Development Team Sponsor.]]></title>
        <id>https://betaflight.com/blog/HQProp - Development Team Sponsor Review</id>
        <link href="https://betaflight.com/blog/HQProp - Development Team Sponsor Review"/>
        <updated>2024-01-01T18:23:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Founded in 2012, HQProp are devoted to supplying the RC community with High Quality props. This brand has been fundamental to the development of the FPV quadcopter hobby by producing cutting edge designs over the whole range of drone size and uses, and they are a popular choice in the Betaflight development team.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Founded in 2012, HQProp are devoted to supplying the RC community with High Quality props. This brand has been fundamental to the development of the FPV quadcopter hobby by producing cutting edge designs over the whole range of drone size and uses, and they are a popular choice in the Betaflight development team.</p>
<p>We are therefore delighted to partner with them as an offical Betaflight Team Sponsor.</p>
<p>Some comments from developers:</p>
<p>SugarK:</p>
<p><em>“Been a fan of HQ and their props for a long time. I love the way they are easy to bend back with the simple shapes which is a big plus in racing. I race ultralite quads and the Ethix range has the perfect range of sub 4g props with different amounts of pitch to suit all the different tracks i might fly. Having been in the hobby a long time the owner of HQ is a real gentleman and very supportive of the hobby, so he was the first person I reached out to when I started looking for sponsors for the Betaflight Dev team”..</em></p>
<p>Vitroid:</p>
<p><em>“I love the J37 and P3.5 for all of my 5” builds, and the 3x2x3 for my 3” practice rig. So far a set has outlived an arm or two! HQ did an amazing job”</em></p>
<p>Limon:</p>
<p><em>“R36 is my favourite prop ever. R38 are also good. They are very durable for racing and crashing, well-designed to be fast enough, but not too fast draining the battery. R36 is an awesome combination of authority, power, and style. HQProp is always super supportive for droneracing community, love that!”</em></p>
<p>Un!t:</p>
<p><em>“Rocking R37 and R38 for all my 5”. The R37 work perfectly for freestyle, when i want a little bit faster, the R38 are just perfect. Also after a crash, you bend them back and they are nearly as new! Love them!”</em></p>
<p>SupaflyFPV:</p>
<p><em>“I fly HQ J37 props exclusively for 5” freestyle because they have an awesome feel and balance - J for the Juice...HQ are quality by name and quality by nature. Thanks Zhong ”</em></p>]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Speed Record for “Fastest ground speed by a battery-powered remote-controlled (RC) quadcopter.”]]></title>
        <id>https://betaflight.com/blog/New World Record for Fastest Drone</id>
        <link href="https://betaflight.com/blog/New World Record for Fastest Drone"/>
        <updated>2024-01-01T18:23:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Its simply a case of "ICYMI". Yes folks Betaflight, albeit an earlier version than current, was the firmware behind the most recent record breaking success story for the “Fastest ground speed by a battery-powered remote-controlled (RC) quadcopter.”.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Its simply a case of "ICYMI". Yes folks Betaflight, albeit an earlier version than current, was the firmware behind the most recent record breaking success story for the “Fastest ground speed by a battery-powered remote-controlled (RC) quadcopter.”.</p>
<p>The Guinness World Records has granted the title to Ryan Lademann (USA), using his custom built drone called the XLR V3 Red. This drone powered its way to the record books by hitting 224mph (360kmh). Yes thats right folks this drone nearly hit 200knots (195knots). Many light aircraft would love to reach those speeds. The record attempt was made in Scottsdale, Arizona, USA, on 8 November 2022. What a way to finish out the year.</p>
<p>The team here at Betaflight congratulate Ryan on his successful attempt, and are very happy the firmware played a small part in that success. now how can we get Ryan to update his firmware ;).</p>
<p>For some more details on the attempt:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>For a clip of the attempt: <a href="https://youtu.be/J3WwtByvSI0?t=21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://youtu.be/J3WwtByvSI0?t=21</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If your are so inclined the black box log of the attempt can be analysed here: <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1K1JLV_f3W0z1dRSP84hw3UEqv5Fc_b5P/view" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://drive.google.com/file/d/1K1JLV_f3W0z1dRSP84hw3UEqv5Fc_b5P/view</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Don't forget to check out Ryan's page for more details on the drone: <a href="https://quad-star-drones.com/xlr-v3/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://quad-star-drones.com/xlr-v3/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>And last but not least, the details from GWR themselves: <a href="https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/world-records/464800-fastest-ground-speed-by-a-battery-powered-remote-controlled-quadcopter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">https://www.guinnessworldrecords.com/world-records/464800-fastest-ground-speed-by-a-battery-powered-remote-controlled-quadcopter</a></p>
</li>
</ul>]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>